A Guide to the John P. Hervey papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA166
Rockefeller Archive Center
John P. Hervey papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1935-1984, undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Hervey, John P.
FA166
0.44 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
John P. Hervey was a professional electrical engineer who became the Senior Electrical Engineer at the Rockefeller Institute's Jacques Loeb Laboratory in Woods Hole, Massachusetts. He began his career as an assistant professor of biophysics at Cornell Medical College and then became an associate professor at Johns Hopkins University.
Detlev Bronk, president of the RI, hired Hervey in order to strengthen the Electronics Laboratory to better serve the needs of neurophysiologists. Hervey worked in Woods Hole on long-term projects while his assistants, C. Yang and then Robert Schoenfeld (1956), ran the laboratory in New York.
Hervey died on May 19, 1982.
Arrangement note
Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 H446
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Electrical engineering; Engineering; Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.); Medical education; Neurosciences; Medical research; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University; Hervey, John P.; Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
- Clippings, 1959-1984; 1; 1 folder
  Scope and Contents note
  Subjects include the Woods Hole Laboratory.
  Arrangement note
  Not arranged.
  - Clippings, 1959-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1934-1983; 2; 5 folders
  Includes correspondence and memos.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by institution.
  - Cornell University, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Johns Hopkins, 1948-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania, University of, 1935-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller University, 1969-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Woods Hole, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence, 1949-1984, undated; 3; 0.2 Cubic Feet
  Arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent.
  - Brink, Frank, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bronk, Detlev and family, 1956-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Condolence Letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Connelly, Clarence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Eisenberg, Laurence, 1971-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gasser, Herbert S., 1949-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Harper, Harry, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hartline, H.K., 1967-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Horsfall, Frank, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mauro, Alexander, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oberholzer, Rudi, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rivers, Thomas, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Schoenfeld, Robert, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Photographs, undated; 4; 2 folders
  Includes photographs of Detlev Bronk and John Hervey.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by person.
  - Bronk, Detlev, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hervey, John P., undated (Box 1, Folder 22)